# **Steve Tucker**

# Software Developer | Product Manager | Marketing & Sales Innovator

+1 (917) 605-9366 | Midtown, Atlanta, GA | stevenstucker@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/stevenstucker

### **SUMMARY**

**Full Stack developer** designing, building, and maintaining efficient, reusable, and reliable code for web, responsive web and mobile apps. Expert in software development and product lifecycles including all aspects of coding, product management, ecommerce, monetization, marketing, PR, influencer programs and related to create raving fans and drive revenues. Excellent communicator, expert in translating business requirements into technical solutions with end-user focus.

**MBA**, software developer, **product manager** with tenure at **Apple** (set up first offices in India), **ATARI** (led \$70 MM of software development and generated \$150 MM in annual revenues) and **AT&T** (product manager responsible for launching DIRECTV Now and AT&T THANKS to over 100 MM customers and led \$50 MM software development projects).

### **Coding & Development**

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Bootstrap, jQuery, JSON
- AJAX, Node.js, Express.js
- React.js, C#, Java, ASP.NET
- Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB
- Command Line, Git, API's
- AWS, Azure, Google Cloud
- MERN, Web & Mobile Apps

### **Product & Brand Management**

- Web Apps, Mobile Apps
- Agile Development
- Project Management
- Market Research, Big Data
- Analytics, Journey Maps
- UI/UX, Product Roadmap
- Business Modeling, MVP
- Personas, Wireframing

### **Marketing & Sales**

- Marketing & Sales Strategy
- Influencer Marketing
- PR & Communications
- Events & Promotions
- Leadership, Team Building
- Creative Direction
- Cross Functional Teams
- Monetization & Sales

In addition to software development and marketing success expertly equipped with a proven history managing multimillion-dollar budgets, P&L, monetization strategies, management (30+ personnel), cross-functional team leadership, international business, remote working environments and the overall creation & innovation process.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Digital Cowboy LLC, Atlanta, GA

Jan 2008 - Present

- Build, create and deploy cloud-based apps with mobile and web tools and tech including; HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, JSON and client-side frameworks such as Angular, React and MySQL and MongoDB databases.
- Front-end and back-end developer expert in translating business requirements into technical solutions with end-user focus.
- Support additional client needs with marketing, e-commerce, PR, earned media, branding, digital, social media and influencer marketing, consumer insights, lead generation creative direction, copy, content and digital experience (UI/UX).
- Expert in all aspects of product and software development through to launch including; concept ideation and innovation, business and financial modeling, capital raise, PR, communications, tech strategy, tech development, e-newsletters, analytics, branding, creative direction, marketing and monetization strategy from to go-to-market through rapid growth.

# **Product Marketing Director**

MAGIX Software GmbH, Atlanta, GA / Berlin, Germany

Jan 2017 - Present

- Manage and develop USA territory for creator software brands, achieved 20% CAGR via earned, paid media and strategic partnerships to drive e-commerce revenues, new channel and product development direction.
- Drive activation via film and music festivals, online PR, earned media and branded content with influencers.
- Execute and create editorial, advertorial, brand engagement, sponsorships, affiliate and digital campaigns for VEGAS Pro (pro video editing software), ACID Pro, SOUND Forge Pro (professional DAW music creator software).
- Develop high ROI digital media plans, reporting, analytics and outreach with major publisher networks, influencers and bloggers targeting pro video, film, music and entertainment industries.
- Created and produced Facebook Live series for branding, affiliate sales and e-commerce with social influencers.
- Channel development strategy and execution for K-12 and Higher-Ed market penetration into creator schools, universities and institutes to activate brands within target community driving new multimillion-dollar channels.

STEVE TUCKER 1

# **Product Manager**

AT&T Inc, Atlanta, GA

Oct 2014 – Dec 2017

- Led digital experience and innovation for ATT.com, DIRECTV NOW, connected devices, IoT, smart TV, web and mobile video streaming products including myAT&T mobile app innovation for mobile, TV and Internet products.
- Launched AT&T THANKS digital loyalty program, reaching 100 million views, 15 million engagements for 100+ million customers. Activate big data and consumer insights for personalization driving increased revenues.
- Drive product innovation in coordination with cross functional business teams across global business owners, sales, marketing, legal, IT and operations teams for product integration across diverse business units.
- Responsible for MyATT, att.com (\$14 billion revenue) services and e-commerce across web and mobile apps.
- Support the implementation and standardization of agile development into organization, drove release cycles for strategic updates and daily releases for fresh brand experience. Drive cross-functional team leadership.
- Responsible for UI/UX, brand copy, customer journeys, brand creative and all product development activities.

# **Director of Marketing**

The Steadman Clinic, Vail, CO

Jul 2012 - Mar 2014

- Aligned marketing to maximize ROI, implemented full-time org, media planning, processes, reporting and analytics for measurement. \$1 million budget. Revenues increased 25%.
- Increased reach and engagement 1,000% through press relations and digital / measured media campaigns.
- Led brand redesign, creative direction, organized marketing and operation resources to increase engagement.
- Teamed with internal stakeholders (Doctors, Scientists, Researchers) to define goals, ROI and success metrics.
- Directed international event planning for press interviews, sports (cycling, skiing, outdoor sports), research and non-profit million-dollar fundraisers for the clinic and SPRI research institute 501C(3) philanthropy initiatives.
- Developed integrated marketing campaigns (under HIPAA compliance) for patient education and fundraising.

# **VP Marketing and Product Development**

FanCandy, New York, NY

Jun 2010 - Jul 2012

- Drove business strategy, sales, product development, marketing, branding and partnerships for this VC-backed startup, a mobile and social brand engagement and sports betting platform.
- Created first-ever mobile social app for online, mobile and social play tied to live TV events and fantasy sports.
- Supported capital development and funding for \$1.5+ million seed round and related financial modeling.

### Sr. Director of Marketing

Crestron Electronics, Rockleigh, NJ

Sep 2010- Mar 2011

- Hired to disrupt "analog" thinking within marketing to drive revenues via digital, social marketing and PR. Lead generation increased 100% through website redesign and sales funnel. Sales increased 20% to \$80 million.
- Managed and directed team of 20+ designers, web development, UI/UX, back-end, PR, social, project management and copywriters. Implemented agile development into organization.

# **VP Business Development**

Games 2 Win, New York, NY / Mumbai, India

May 2009 - Aug 2010

- Brought on to drive sales, increase market share and develop distribution partners. Provided product management, marketing and PR strategy to accelerate growth in USA territory.
- Delivered \$1 million from direct sales quota and ad partnerships as sole sales representative covering all of USA territory. Efforts doubled audience from 13 to 25 million monthly uniques. Became a top-25 online publisher.

# **Chief Revenue and Marketing Officer**

Worldwide Biggies Inc, New York, NY

Aug 2008 - May 2009

• Founded by Albie Hecht (former President of Nickelodeon Entertainment) this \$12 million VC-backed startup developed advertising, mobile apps, games, TV, film and branded content for audience engagement.

STEVE TUCKER 2

• Recruited directly by founder as integral part of monetization strategy team to build sales and marketing programs. Delivered \$3+ million in revenues from product sales, development contracts and advertising sales.

#### **VP Global Ad Sales**

IGA Worldwide Inc, New York, NY / London, UK

Jan 2008 – Aug 2008

- VC-backed interactive ad agency raised \$50+ million. Recruited by IGA after developing video game industries first ingame ad campaigns (Nokia, Ben Sherman) while at Atari in 2007. Hired to lead sales, channel marketing, implement salesforce.com, reporting, process and controls to drive revenues and increase market share.
- Generated \$4+ million in revenues from direct sales and team initiatives direct to brand and via agency media sales. Led 12+ ad executives, account managers, sales support, creative services, marketing and PR staff.

# Sr. Director of Marketing and Business Operations

ATARI Inc, New York, NY

Aug 2005 - Dec 2007

- During tenure we became a first-mover to launch in-game ads, online games and digital distribution direct to consumer e-commerce and online play. Generated over \$150 million in revenues from North American product sales (packaged / online media) and managed \$20 million budget. Walmart, Best Buy, GameStop retail partners.
- Directed team of 25 personnel for product marketing. Online, print, TV and traditional media managing individual brand budgets of \$10+ million from green light to sell through at major retailers. Led consumer insight activities through focus groups, product, concept and package testing and all opt-in email-marketing initiatives.

# **VP Business Development and Product Management**

Z-Tel Technologies Inc, Atlanta, GA / New York, NY

Mar 1998 – Dec 2004

- Inaugural member (employee #10) of startup that raised over \$300 million to launch a SaaS / dot-com tech firm and part of team that successfully took company public in an IPO in 1999. Grew revenues to \$300 million while company reached 2,000+ employees. Hired to lead brand management and product development for software development, drive market share and build operations from startup through to publicly traded company.
- Produced \$25+ million in annual revenues from direct sales quota and national MLM channel affiliates. Created industry's first Internet-only personalized content and communication speech recognition SaaS platform.

### Manager, Global Pre-sales Engineering

SITA / Equant, Atlanta, GA / Paris, France

Sep 1996 - Mar 1998

- Pre-sales support for voice and data solutions proved instrumental to drive new multinational business channel sales revenues. Worked hand-in-hand with global sales teams and R&D to develop innovative solutions and close sales opportunities. Select customers included Japan Airlines, Hyatt and United Nations as example.
- Launched and directed global pre-sales team and sales operations delivering \$5+ million revenue with sales executives. Developed training curriculum for evangelization of international firms for new media platforms.

**Sr. Project Manager** (awarded Apple Internship during spring semester in graduate school in 1993) Apple Inc, Cupertino, CA / Charlotte, NC May 1993 – Sep 1996

- Responsible for launching emerging markets to support international growth and manage N. and S. American offices. Hired to manage enterprise solutions for marketing, sales and logistics operations.
- Pioneered emerging market projects including startup sales, software development and marketing operations.
- Established first-ever India operations in Bangalore for sales, marketing and software development operations.

### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Coding Certificate, Expected May 2019, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

MBA, Cum Laude, Dec 1993, The University of North Carolina at Charlotte, Charlotte, NC Graduate Teaching and Research Assistant, Belk College of Business, MIS and Communications departments.

Bachelor of Science, Industrial Management, Dec 1988, Clemson University, Clemson, SC

STEVE TUCKER 3